BRYAN NILSEN

646.221.1321

🔀 bryannilsen@gmail.com

github.com/BryanNilsen

linkedin.com/in/bryan-nilsen

bryannilsen.com

Full-Stack Software Developer

About

Enthusiastic team player, creative thinker, and effective communicator with a growth mindset and expanding skillset in software development. Eager to learn as well as teach, coach, and motivate others. I thrive on positivity and high-five often.

Bachelor's Degree in Art and Design with related experience, including nearly two years in Ireland designing and developing websites. Proficient with Adobe graphics suite including UI/UX software. Skilled painter with an eye for detail. Average guitarist with a desire to shred.

Worked extensively as a stenographer, covering primarily civil litigation matters. Managed tight deadlines while working closely with counsel in highly-confidential settings. Excellent communication skills.

My return to web development reignited a passion for learning, problem solving, and collaborating with others.

Tech Skills

EXPERIENCE WITH:

- HTML / CSS (flexbox and grid)
- Javascript / React (classes and hooks)
- · Python / Django
- C# / ASP.Net Core
- SQL
- Visual Studio / VS Code
- · Git Version Control / Github
- · Working with APIs
- NPM Packages
- · HTTP-Server / JSON-Server
- Phaser
- Webpack / Browserify / Grunt
- Firebase

PROGRAMMING FUNDAMENTALS:

- · Troubleshooting / Debugging
- · Reading Documentation
- Windows / Mac Software Installations
- AGILE Methodology
- · Commenting Code

CSS FRAMEWORKS:

- Bootstrap / ReactStrap
- Material UI / Semantic UI

DESIGN SOFTWARE:

• Adobe Photoshop / Illustrator / XD

Related Experience

Junior Instructor - Software Developer

Nashville Software School | Apr 2019 - Present

- 12 months assisting lead instructors, teaching client-side software development concepts including HTML, CSS, GIT version control, JavaScript and React - (both class and function-based with hooks)
- 4+ months assisting lead instructors, teaching server-side technologies including Python, Django, C#, ASP.Net Core, and SQL Server
- Acting as product manager and Scrum leader during group projects, leading sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and sprint retros utilizing Agile methodologies
- Coaching students through troubleshooting and debugging techniques
- · Contributing to open source course curriculum
- · Assisting admissions team in conducting interviews of prospective students
- 4+ months working remote via Zoom, providing lectures and code debugging

Projects

MCA - Concert Tracking App - Server-Side Capstone

MCA, My Concert App, is a web application allowing users to search for and log all of the concerts they've attended. Once a concert is added to their account, users can view setlists, add their comments, rate their experience, and upload any personal photos or videos of the event with the ability to make them public or private.

Built with: Python with the Django framework using VS Code editor. **Design, Prototyping, and Styling:** Adobe XD with custom CSS.

Artist Search Functionality: Setlist.fm API with Postman for testing gueries.

Database Development: SQLite and DB Browser

Repo: https://github.com/BryanNilsen/MCA-MyConcertApp

SwishList - Basketball Shot-Tracking App - Client-Side Capstone

Swishlist is a responsive single-page basketball shot-tracking app allowing users to log their workouts and shots using a dynamically-generated basketball court map. Individual statistics are calculated and presented with ranked leaderboards in addition to the user's profile and motivational quotes for additional inspiration.

Built with: Javascript with React framework using VS Code editor **Design, Prototyping, and Styling:** Adobe XD with custom CSS

Database Development: |SON-Server with Postman for testing queries

Repo: https://github.com/BryanNilsen/Swishlist-React

Demo: swishlist-demo.herokuapp.com > login email: test@test.com / password: test

Hack-O-Lantern - Game - Hackathon Team Project

Hack-O-Lantern is a pumpkin-controlled game built for the 2019 NSS Halloween Hackathon. In under 42 hours, I learned Phaser and helped my team build a game where the main software dev character moves back and forth collecting the letters N-S-S while avoiding bugs. In addition to a majority of the gameplay features, I added graphical elements and mapped the keyboard to the Makey-Makey which enabled the pumpkin controllers.

Built with: Javascript with Phaser framework using VS Code editor

Design, Prototyping, Styling: Adobe Photoshop

Repo: https://github.com/BryanNilsen/Hackolantern

BRYAN NILSEN

Full-Stack Software Developer

646.221.1321

github.com/BryanNilsen

bryannilsen@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/bryan-nilsen

bryannilsen.com

Education

Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Web Development Six-Month, Full-Time Bootcamp

New York Career Institute

AOS - Court Reporting

NC State University College of Design

Bachelor of Arts - Art and Design

Volunteer

Head Coach - Basketball

2016-17 - ages 5-6

2017-18 - ages 7-8

2018-19 - ages 7-8

2019-20 - ages 9-10

Assistant Coach - Football

2017 - ages 7-8

2018 - ages 7-8 / 9 -10

2019 - ages 9-10

Training

Full-Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School | Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

Full-time software development bootcamp focusing on full-stack web development fundamentals and problem solving, with final half of program executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology.

- Built single-page client-side apps using React, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Developed server-side applications using Python, Django, and SQL
- Applied OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects reflecting real-world business problems
- Utilized source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Learned and applied JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Implemented task automation with Grunt, linting with ESLint, and module bundling with Browserify
- Designed and wireframed applications using Adobe XD
- Planned applications by white boarding dependencies and building ERDs

Work History

Director of Business Development / Client RelationsAlpha Reporting Corporation | Oct 2016 - Sep 2018 | Nashville, TN

- Managed local Nashville branch of court reporting firm
- · Communicated directly with clients to handle requests and/or concerns
- · Maintained local office, supplies, computer equipment, and peripherals
- · Coordinated and performed videoconference equipment tests for depositions
- Presented company information at industry conferences
- Created text copy and visual content for social media campaign

Court Reporter / Stenographer - Independent Contractor Various Court Reporting Agencies | Jul 2004 - Sep 2016 - New York, NY

- Transcribed and produced verbatim transcripts of legal testimony for depositions, hearings, arbitrations, and various court matters, including presidential speeches
- Provided instant, real-time transcripts to counsel during live testimony
- Frequently personally requested to cover complex and confidential assignments
- Consistently met client transcript delivery deadlines
- · Managed and organized work schedule and backlog with multiple reporting firms
- Performed all duties in accordance with the NCRA Code of Professional Ethics

Freelance Graphic Designer / Web Developer

The Coastal Group / Redscope LLC | Apr 2002 - Dec 2002 - New York City

- Wireframing and website design, hand-coding in combination with Dreamweaver
- Utilized DTP software QuarkXpress / inDesign for typography and content layout
- Prepared product images for web and print catalog: resizing, silhouetting

Graphic Artist / Engraving Consultant / Web DeveloperPrecision Design Partners / The Ardenza Group | 1999 - 2001 - Dublin, Ireland

- · Designed, wireframed, and built websites for local Irish businesses
- HTML, CSS, Flash with Actionscript
- Advised on equipment setup and instructed proper glass and crystal engraving techniques on-site at Waterford Crystal location
- Created custom artwork using traditional hand-drawn techniques in combination with image editing software
- Networked local office computers and peripherals

Graphic Artist

Rayzist Photomask, Inc | Mar 1998 - Jul 1999 - Vista, CA

- Developed custom artwork for glass and crystal engraving process
- · Interacted directly with clients to understand needs and deliver desired results
- Taught monthly seminars on graphic software, engraving process and techniques